<?xml version = "1.0"?>

<!--cpsc_catalog.xml - Computer Science Course Catalog-->

<catalog><course>
<1234567890123456789012345678901234567890123456789012345678901234567890 12345678901234567890/>
<number>101</number>
<title>Introduction To Computer Systems</title>   
<credits>3</credits>   
<description>Introduction to the basic concepts and techniques of how computers are used to help solve problems; discussion of all components of a complete computer system, including equipment, programs, data, procedures, and personnel; use of applications packages including word processing, electronic spreadsheet, and data base system on IBM-compatible personal computers. No prior exposure to computers assumed</description>   <prereq>none</prereq>   <offered>Fall, Spring, Summer</offered></course><course>   <number>110</number>   <title>Computer Programming With Business Applications</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Introduction to the basic principles of computer programming and the application of programming solving business-oriented problems.  Topics include algorithm development, basic control structures, procedures, arrays, records, graphic user interface design, and file processing.  Applications in Visual Basic will be included.  No prior exposure to computer programming is assumed</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 101</prereq>  <offered>Fall, Spring</offered></course><course>   <number>121</number>  <title>Introduction To Programming</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>The development and implementation of reliable and efficient algorithms is presented; structured programming in an object-oriented language is performed</description>   <prereq>none</prereq>   <offered>Fall, Spring</offered></course><course>   <number>122</number>   <title>Intermediate Programming</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Proper programming style, expression, and documentation, begun in CPSC 121, will be continued considering additional techniques such as string processing, recursion, advanced searching and sorting, and abstract data types.  Analysis of algorithms will be introduced along with with basic data structures</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 121</prereq>   <offered>Spring</offered></course><course>   <number>205</number>   <title>C++ Programming</title>   <credits>1</credits>   <description>An introduction to programming in C++ specifically geared towards non-computer science applications.  Emphasis on coding programs in C++ while contrasting it with other higher-level languages</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 121</prereq>   <offered>Fall</offered></course><course>   <number>210</number>   <title>Computer Systems and Systems Level Programming</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>An introduction to computer hardware and architecture is presented using assembly level programming to emphasize architectural concepts. An introduction to C++ is also included</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 122</prereq>   <offered>Fall</offered></course><course>   <number>211</number>   <title></title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Building upon the introduction to C++ programming in CPSC210, higher level features of C++ will be presented, including object-oriented design using classes, inheritance and polymorphism, templates, exception handling and the standard template library</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 210</prereq>   <offered>Spring</offered></course><course>   <number>310</number>   <title>Numerical Analysis (same as Mathematics 310)</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Programmable algorithms, with error analysis, for: solving non-linear equations, systems of linear equations, matrix calculations, polynomial interpolation, least squares approximation, and numerical integration. Programming assignments</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 121, 205, or 210. Mathematics 221</prereq>   <offered>Spring, even-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>340</number>   <title>Management Information Systems (same as Management 340)</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Consider the entire set of steps necessary to implement or alter an information system. Included is problem analysis and definition, developing specifications, system design, implementation, control, and maintenance. It emphasizes management considerations, as well as structured systems techniques and technological factors</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 101, Management 101</prereq>   <offered>Fall, odd-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>341</number>   <title>Database Management (same as Management 341)</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Students analyze techniques for organizing, storing, and retrieving large amounts of related data. Conceptual analysis as well as practical applications on computers are presented. Emphasis is placed on management control practices concerning security, privacy, integrity, and the maintenance of the data</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 122, Management 101</prereq>   <offered>Spring, even-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>342</number>   <title>E-Commerce (same as Management 342)</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Introduction to the use of computer networks as a medium for commercial activity.  Topics include technological infrastructure, Internet retailing and advertisement, business-to-business commerce, consumer behavior, corporate strategy, and all the legal and societal issues of electronic commerce</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 101</prereq>   <offered>Fall</offered></course><course>   <number>343</number>   <title>System Analysis and Design (same as Management 343)</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Introduction to system development with particular emphasis on the design and analysis phases of the process.  Topics include feasibility analysis, requirements analysis and definition, interface design, design tools, prototyping, and design tools.  Implementation of systems will also be discussed.  Emphasis is placed on management issues in systems development including economic, personnel, and marketing concerns</description>   <prereq>Computer Science/Management 340</prereq>   <offered>Fall</offered></course><course>   <number>398-399</number>   <title>Computer Science Internship </title>   <credits>3-15</credits>   <description>The integration of classroom theory with practical work experience under which students have specific periods of attendance at college and specific periods of employment, either full- or part-time, with or without pay. Credit may vary from three to 15 credits, but no more than four credits may be counted toward major requirements, with additional credits counted as free electives. Open only to Computer Science majors with approval of the department chair and the Vice President for Academic Affairs</description>   <prereq>none</prereq>   <offered>Fall, Spring, Summer</offered></course><course>   <number>401</number>   <title>Data Structures</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Data structures, concepts, and algorithms and their application to information storage and retrieval and list processing are discussed</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>As needed</offered></course><course>   <number>405</number>   <title>Decision Support Systems (same as Management 405) </title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Introduction to the development of effective decision-making systems and the application of technology in supporting the information needs of such systems.  Topics include decision modeling, groupware, data warehousing, data mining, and the use of artificial intelligence, expert systems, and neural networks in decision-making</description>   <prereq>Computer Science/Management 343</prereq>   <offered>Spring</offered></course><course>   <number>407</number>   <title>Operating Systems</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>An introduction to the basic components of operating systems, including functions, types, and structures of operating systems, concurrent programming, process and resource control, and security</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>Spring, odd-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>410</number>   <title>Software Engineering</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Introduction to the models and issues concerned with the development of high-quality software. Application of software engineering methodology to the planning, specification, design, development, testing, and delivery of a large software project</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>Fall, even-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>411</number>   <title>Rapid Application Development</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Fast development of large-scale applications programs in the focus of this course.  Utilizes visual programming languages and CASE tools, students explore the topics of user interface design, relational database applications, dynamic link libraries, and network programming.  Students are exposed to standards-based development</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>Spring, odd-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>420</number>   <title>Programming Languages</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Introduction to the general concepts of programming language design and implementation; underlying principles of various types of languages are discussed; exposure to various programming languages not used in other courses</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>Fall, even-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>430</number>   <title>Computer Organization</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>An in-depth study of logic circuits beginning with elementary gates and flip-flops and moving through more complex circuits such as register, counters, adders, and decoders; an introduction to integrated circuits used in digital computers; memory and I/O subsystems</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>Fall, odd-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>431</number>   <title>Networks and Data Communications</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>Introduction to underlying concepts and principles of computer networks; network topology, communications protocols (ISO/OSI, TCP/IP), LANs and WANs applications such as e-mail and the World Wide Web</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>Fall, even-numbered years</offered></course><course>   <number>440</number>   <title>Computer Graphics</title>   <credits>3</credits>   <description>The display of images to a computer's output device is discussed; students are introduced to the basic principles and algorithms of graphics with particular emphasis on 3-D imaging; illumination and animation are discussed</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>As needed</offered></course><course>   <number>491</number>   <title>Seminar: Special Problems</title>   <credits>1-3</credits>   <description>Open to qualified students with special areas of interest</description>   <prereq>none</prereq>   <offered>As needed</offered></course><course>   <number>492</number>   <title>Computer Science Seminar</title>   <credits>1</credits>   <description>Selection of an acceptable computer science topic, research, and presentation of the research findings in written and oral form</description>   <prereq>Computer Science 211</prereq>   <offered>Fall</offered></course><course>   <number>501</number>   <title>Independent Study in Computer Science</title>   <credits>1-8</credits>   <prereq>none</prereq>   <offered>As needed</offered></course></catalog>